<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- 
 @package polyphony.docs
 
 @copyright Copyright &copy; 2005, Middlebury College
 @license http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html GNU General Public License (GPL)
 @version $Id: changelog.xml,v 1.56.2.16 2006/08/15 17:28:28 adamfranco Exp $
 -->
 
<!DOCTYPE changelog SYSTEM "../dtds/changelog.dtd">

<changelog name="Polyphony ChangeLog">
	<version number="0.6.5" date="2006-08-15">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repository: Now returns false instead of throwing an error if the 
			Asset with the specified id does not exist.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.6.4" date="2006-08-11">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Now can force cookie usage to prevent accidental or intentional 
			session hijacking by the passing of session ids in the url.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			New abstract action for RSS feeds. Handles some input validation,
			formatting, and authentication.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Logs: Added RSS feeds of logs.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Logs: Now has a button to clear date limits.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Removed unneeded parameter from file and thumbnail urls.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			File/Thumbnail view: Now forces HTTP authentication for thumbnails 
			if the user is not authenticated.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.6.3" date="2006-08-04">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Importer: Now doesn't generate null thumbnails for multi-page PDF files.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Basket: Can now view basket contents in viewer.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			PrimitiveIO: Now doesn't die when users enter data that cannot be
			made into a valid value object.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Wizard/PrimitiveIO: Now doesn't show the 'new' field for SelectOrNew
			components when displaying the starting-text.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.6.2" date="2006-08-02">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Importer: Now ignores and doesn't import files beginning with periods, 
			which are usually hidden files.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.6.1" date="2006-07-21">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Importer: Fixed default types.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Importer: Adding the Files-Only repository importer to allow the importing of files with no metadata.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Importer: Fixed a parse error.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Wizard: Adding new WComponentCollection class that can wrap other components.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			FileDownloading: Now adds filenames appropriately or 'Untitled' even 
			if the file doesn't have a name.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.6.0" date="2006-06-16">
		<change author='adam'>
			Basket/Selection images are now show bordered placeholders before 
			they are loaded.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Basket/Selection images are now resized -- albeit only one dimension
			-- in IE.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			ResultPrinter: Now uses skipNext() and count() methods when iterating
			if all items are authorized to print.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			StatusStars: Moved output buffer jumping methods to the RequestContext
			as ob_jump() and ob_land() from Chris's StatusStars. StatusStars is now in
			harmoni/core/utilities.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			StatusStars: Now will print a label if requested.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			DataManagerGUI: AuthoritativeValues addition is now an AuthorizationFunction.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Wizard: Can now call setEnabled() on RepeatableComponentCollections
			and have the intended effect.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Wizard: Can now change Add/Remove button labels for Repeatable Components.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Wizard: Verified change inputs are now set to be checked for new values
			by default.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Wizard: onchange items are now added with addOnChange() rather than 
			overwritten with setOnchange(). Same with setOnClick() going to addOnClick().
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Wizard: Added an addConfirm() method to EventButtons and Selects to allow
			prompting for user-confirmation.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Wizard: Now Select or new fields show either the option OR new, not both.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			WizardAction: now getWizard() will have the same cachename translation
			as was in the runWizard() method.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			Help: Improving the parsing and display of help files to support
			relative links to images, stylesheets, and other files. Better
			generation of menus too.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Logging: Ensured that logging is now ready for use before attempting
			to log errors.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.5.2" date="2006-05-26">
		<change author='adam'>
			ResultPrinter pagination now matches background styles.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Edit-authorization screen now limits each level of the hierarchy to
			ten nodes to prevent being overwhelmed (and timing out) if there
			are many child nodes.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Selection view now better matches the collection view.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Basket/Selection now has an empty link.
		</change>
		<change author='chris'>
			All importers log their actions and errors appropriately.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.5.1" date="2006-05-19">
		<new author='adam'>
			RepositoryInOutModules: Now provides for displaying thumbnails for 
			particular file Records.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Wizard: now suports dropdown-menu reordering rather than just
			move-up/move-down.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Repository Search Modules now support forced setting of values from 
			from a session cache.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			"Basket" is now being displayed as "Selection"
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Result printers now pull more from the common abstract class.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.5.0" date="2006-05-05">
		<change author='adam'>
			Reworked the basket library be more straight-forward, getting rid of 
			the uneeded "BasketManager" and putting all of the functionality in 
			the "Basket" singleton.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Made the Add-Asset-To-Basket process work via AJAX rather than reloading
			the page.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Added the WSelectOrNew class to provide an interface element in which
			a choice could be made or new value could be added.
		</new>
		<change author='chris'>
			Importer class now uses StatusStars to keep track of progress and 
			keep user informed
		</change>
		<new author='chris'>
			StatusStars class added, is a very simple asterisk status bar,
			created for the importer, but works anywhere. (direct output so no
			apache related timeouts)
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Now caches resized versions of images.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.4.1" date="2005-02-09">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed return by reference errors that threw notices in PHP 4.4
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed url '.' to '_' conversion errors.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.4.0" date="2005-01-10">
		<change author='adam'>
			Agents &amp; Authorizations: Added, edited, and reworked aspects of 
			editing and lookup for faster cleaner and more sensible interfacing.
		</change>
		<change author='chris'>
			Login: modified the login process so that it is more consistent and 
			understandable.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Result Printers: now capable of configurable display.
		</change>
		<change author='chris'>
			Printers: all links and other clickable things do what should be 
			expected of clicking on them.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Validator: fixed rules and moved some validations
		</change>
		<new author='chris'>
			Created help files for importing and exporting, along with examples
			and dtds for the different types of importers.  They are available
			on sf.net in the appropriate locations.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			HelpBrowser system.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Added Wizard components to support repeatable values as well as
			'confirmed-change' linked checkboxes and fields.  Modified I/O 
			modules to function with system.
		</new>
		<change author='chris'>
			Modified the implementation of the repeatable wizard components so 
			that everything is elegant and makes more sense, generally more 
			usable.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Now using GUI Block level constants such as EMPHAZISED_BLOCK instead 
			of 'Block 3'.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Optimizations to speed loading of thumbnails.
		</change>
		<change author='chris'>
			Basket &amp; Exporter: Together at last, exporting assets from anywhere
			in the system by adding them to the basket and exporting the basket.
		</change>
		<new author='chris'>
			Basket: New functionality for clearing the basket, adding multiple
			and single files to the basket.
		</new>
		<new author='chris'>
			Exporter: XML Exporter is designed to function with XML Importer and
			allows for human readable (XML) backups of the repository system.
			It is also readily extensible to other aspects of our system.
		</new>
		<new author='chris'>
			Importer: XML Importer is capable of populating repositories with
			flexibility, and is readily extended to work with groups and
			authorizations, or any other aspects of our system.  
		</new>
		<change author='chris'>
			Importer: XML importer has been removed from the 
			"RepositoryImporter" classification, and re-designed to be
			extensible to all aspects of our systems.  Tab and Exif are still 
			only available for repository data population.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.3.0" date="2005-10-12">
		<new author='adam'>
			Repository OutputModules now support accessing the first image
			record of an asset as well as a thumbnail.
		</new>
		<new author='niraj'>
			Importers: Abstract, XML, Tab-Delimited, and EXIF fully functioning.
			Batch importing of assets now available.
		</new>
		<new author='chris'>
			Importers: Abstract, XML, Tab-Delimited, and EXIF fully functioning.
			Batch importing of assets now available.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			New "Basket" system for collecting [Asset] Ids during the session.
			The Basket allows for easy user-selection of a large number of items.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Changed the StartupCheck classes to use the new Wizard.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Changed actions to use Everyone and Users group IDs of "edu.middlebury.agents.everyone" and "edu.middlebury.agents.users".
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Wizard now can handle field names with .'s in them.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			RepositoryInputOutputModules now check for the right record interface.
		</fix>
		<change author='gabe'>
			New Wizard system based on nested components. Much more extensible and
			easy-to-use than the old system.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Updating much of Polyphony to support the RequestContext
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Added an abstract Action class-hierarchy to enable the easy creation
			of class-based actions.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.2.2" date="2005-04-14">
		<fix author='adam'>
			clone() is a reserved word in PHP5. All clone methods have been renamed 
			replicate().
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			textdomain() calls now specify NULL instead of no argument to prevent
			PHP Warnings.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			RepositoryInOutModules now don't throw errors.
		</fix>
		<important author='adam'>
			Polyphony now runs on PHP5 and on Win32 systems in addition to PHP4.3 and
			POSIX systems.
		</important>
	</version>
	<version number="0.2.1" date="2005-04-11">
		<change author='adam'>
			Authentication now plays nicely with GET parameters and maintains them
			around during the authentication sequence.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Fixed some references to the non-existant "SharedManager"
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.2.0" date="2005-04-07">
		<change author="adam">
			Reconfigured modules to work with version 2 of the OSIDs.
		</change>
		<change author="adam">
			Authentication now fully uses Harmoni's implementation of the AuthN
			OSID as Harmoni's own Authentication/LoginHandlers have been removed.
		</change>
		<new author="adam">
			Graphical tools have been created for managing hierarchical authorizations.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.1.0" date="2004-10-26">
		<new author='adam'>
			The 'dr' module provides actions for displaying images and thumbnails
			from a Digital Repository, making use of the DRInputOutputModules.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			DRInputOutputModules provide common functions for displaying and 
			editing DigitalRepository records.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			The 'auth' module provides shared actions for logging in and out.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			StartupCheck and ConfigSystem: These should allow easy creation of
			browser-based install/configuration options and setup. They are 
			undocumented and untested.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Languages: Shared actions for generating a "switch language" form,
			as well as the logic for performing that switch.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			The Wizard library provides a system for the generation of dynamic Multi-step
			wizards. The Wizard library handles the catching, storing, and validating
			of form submitions, as well as handle user-progress through the wizard.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Created Polyphony directory structure.
		</new>
	</version>
	
	<authors>
		<name short="gabe">Gabe Schine</name>
		<name short="adam">Adam Franco</name>
		<name short="dobo">Dobo Radichkov</name>
		<name short="nik">Nikitas Stamatopoulos</name>
		<name short="niraj">Niraj Dhungel</name>
		<name short="alex">Alex Chapin</name>
		<name short='chris'>Christopher W. Shubert</name>
	</authors>
	<groupid>82873</groupid>
	<reftypes>
		<reftype name="bug">567473</reftype>
		<reftype name="fr">567476</reftype>
		<reftype name="task"></reftype>
	</reftypes>
</changelog>
